in this video we're going to talk about
segments when posting transactions in GP
and compare that to the experience in
business Central where we will Define
default dimensions on entities like
vendors and customers to create similar
postings and how those same transactions
look on reports and business
Central to begin let's go to GP and post
an invoice re Reed from a vendor for
some recent training supplies we bought
in the transaction window I'll go ahead
and select a vendor this is the vendor
that our training and Consulting
division regularly uses for purchasing
supplies next I'll enter in the vendor
invoice number and the amount of the
purchase once the transaction is posted
we look at the general posting Journal
report on this report we can see we are
posting to the 6150 Supply account and
the division segment is set to 500 which
is our Consulting and training team
now let's look at business Central and
how we can set up default dimensions on
a vendor and how those are used on
transactions and reported on in the
trial balance if you remember from the
segment Dimension setup video the
segments we defined in GP will migrate
to business Central as Dimensions
allowing us to continue to slice and
categorize our transactions being posted
to the main
accounts I'll first go to that same
vendor in business Central that I
migrated from GP using the cloud
migration tool I want to assign the
Consulting and training team as the
default Dimension value for the division
Dimension since again most of the
purchase we make from this vendor are
used by our Consulting and training
team in the dimension window I'll go
ahead and select the division Dimension
and then select the training and
Consulting Dimension
value if I wanted to lock the posting
down further I could set the value
posting to code mandatory which would
indicate that a dimension value must
exist on a transaction for this vendor
for our purposes however I don't want
the system to be that rigid we just want
the dimension value to default on
transactions for
us next let's enter in a purchase
invoice for this vendor similar to how
we did it in GP and look at how that
Dimension value will default onto the
transaction I'll go ahead and select the
purchase journal and enter in my vendor
invoice number again select the vendor
and key in the purchase
amount you can see in the fact boox area
the dimension value has automatically
defaulted onto the transaction for me
before posting any journal in business
Central I can preview the posting to
ensure that the correct accounts are
being posted to similar to clicking the
distributions button in
GP I can see that it's posting to our
supplies account and our 500 division
since that all looks correct I'll go
ahead and post the
invoice now let's look at the trial
balance Dimension report in business
Central in my report option window I've
selected to print the division Dimension
and we filter the report to the supplies
account next I'll choose to view
transactions for today only and for the
Consulting and Training Division
the trial balance report in business
Central allows me to see amounts being
posted to my main accounts similar to GP
as well as allowing me to analyze
transactions by various categories in
this example by division and that's a
quick look at segments and dimension
posting in GP and business
Central to learn more about business
Central see the following resources